Contact

- Nairobi, 30197-0010
- +254727221023
- shadrackipruto@gmail.c om

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- https://github.com /Shadkoech
- linkedin.com/in /koechshadrack

Skills

Python (API, Flask and Django frameworks)

JavaScript (ReactJS), HTML, CSS

MySQL

Git/Version control

Unit Testing, RESTful services, GIT/Version Control

Collaboration: Trello

Prototyping: Figma

Scripting and automation

Laboratory Management

Chemical Analysis

Lean Six Sigma, Good Manufacturing Practices

Technical Documentation

Code Reviews

Testing and Debugging



I am an aspiring software engineer who aims to leverage learned software engineering principles to analyze user requirements and craft tailored solutions for optimal product development.

My aim is to integrate back-end and front-end development to enhance system efficiency and address industry challenges. With three years of work experience, I fully comprehend professional workplace demands. I have exhibited self-drive and leadership through the formulation of SOPs and in-house procedures for a new raw material monitoring section in my previous role.

Work History

2017-09 -2020-10

In-Process Quality Assurance Chemist

Golden Africa Kenya Limited, Nairobi

- Collaborated with laboratory technicians, production personnel and customers to improve product quality and functionality.
- Supervised sampling process to ensure proper sample collection and archiving
- Performed standard and proprietary physical testing and chemical analysis of raw chemical materials and finished products. (§ CPO, CPKO, BPO, RBDPO, PFAD, STEARIN, OLEIN)
- Dispatch quality agent of finished goods, handling market returns as well as market complaints.
- Advised chemists and laboratory technicians on existing and emerging quality control methods to enhance testing and research capabilities.
- Prepared and standardized test solutions and reagents to enable successful testing completion.

2015-04 -2015-09

Process Control Intern

The East Africa Portland Cement EAPCC (Blue Triangle), Kitengela

Soft-skills: Professionalism, Communication, time-management

- Inspection of the raw materials limestone, kunkur fines, iron ore, alumina clay gypsum, coal and HFO.
- Temperature and pressure monitoring in the Atox mill, coal mill, preheated cyclones and kiln.
- Physical measurements of the feeding conveyor belts to ensure coordination with control room.
- Interacted with customers by phone, email, or in-person to provide information.
- Completed research, compiled data, updated spreadsheets, and produced timely reports.
- Analyzed process problems and worked with teams to develop solutions.

Education

Expected in 2024-04

Post-graduate Certification: Software Engineering

ALX-Africa (Holberton School) - Remote Title: Portfolio project on industrial process automation.

Back-end: Django, MySQL

Front-end: React, JS, HTML, CSS

DevOps: Github actions

Platforms: Docker, Figma, Trello, Github

- Completed Coursework:
- * Foundation: C, Git and command line editors
- * Sprint 2: Python, SQL, Algorithms, Bash scripting,

HTML, Regex, Makefiles, Data structures

- * Sprint 3: ORM, web-framework, SSH, SSL, Search algos, Web-server, Restful API
- * Sprint 4: Server management, load-balancing, Firewall, deployment, Post-incidence
- * Sprint 5: Back-end specialization

2017-11 Bachelor of Science: Industrial Chemistry

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture And Tech - Juja - Main Campus

Degree Awarded with Second class Upper

- Member Science club, 2013 to 2020
- Research Project: Determination of Food and Nutritional Value of Balanite aegyptiaca Plant